准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
天堂锅铲
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝  动作快点
SpongeBob, hurry up in there
4297份蟹黄堡
4,297 Krabby Patties
马上就来
coming right up
上菜了
Orders up
铲铲
Spatty
一定要撑住  兄弟
Hang in there, buddy
我来救你
I'll save you
不
No
我蟹黄堡怎么还没上
Where's my Krabby Patty?
对啊
Yeah
干什么拖那么久
What's taking so long?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
餐怎么还没上
Where are my orders?
我
I
我再也翻不了肉饼了
I can't flip patties anymore
你什么
You what?
最好给我解释清楚  小子
You better explain yourself, boy-o
我的锅铲断了  蟹老板
My spatula is broken, Mr. Krabs
没了铲铲  我做不了蟹黄堡
I can't make Krabby Patties without Spatty
事情就这样
Is that all?
锅铲柜那边再拿一把不就行了
Just grab another one from the spatula closet
柜子里的我用不了  蟹老板
I can't cook with those, Mr. Krabs
我得用我自己的锅铲
I need to use my own spatula
随便找的锅铲不行
not just any spatula
知道吗  蟹老板
You see, Mr. Krabs
铲铲十分特别  还十分古老
Spatty is very special and very ancient
在天涯海角的群山之间锻造而成
He was forged deep in the mountains beyond the horizon
位在遥远无际的
in the far-flung land of--
听好了  小子
Listen up, boy-o
我现在每秒都会多亏钱
I'm losing money by the second here
你要怎么解决  我都不稀罕
I don't care what you do
最好给我速战速决
but you better get back in a jiffy
不然我就把你工作全让给海绵汤姆
or I'll just have to give your job to SpongeTom here
我预备好了
I'm prepared
那种事情不要啊
No, anything but that
放心
Don't worry
我会把我锅铲重新锻造好的
I'll get my spatula reforged
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你要去
Where are you--
替我先顶一下  章鱼哥
Hold down the fort for me, Squidward
谢谢
Thanks
谢谢你
Thank you
原来我这么多年来用法都不对
I've been using them wrong all these years
神秘雾山
攀爬风险自负
The Mystical Misty Mountains
总算到了
Finally here
再往山顶走一小段路
And now for a short walk to the top
至少我这背包可没白背
Well, at least I didn't carry this backpack for nothing
太神了
Amazing
来得正好
Right on time
是吗
I am?
没错
You sure are
我来担任你的导游
I'll be your guide today
鲁布导游旅行团
首先要走过这座神奇的鱼造桥
First up, we will cross this amazing fish-made bridge
别怕
Don't worry
就一纸老虎罢了
This is way easier than it looks
在左边的是无穷瘀伤地缝
On your left is the chasm of infinite bruising
太壮观了吧
Isn't that wonderful?
在右边的是冻鱼坑
And on your right, we got the freezing pit
就跟你说很轻松吧
I told you it'd be a breeze
你的表现太神了
You're doing amazing
继续前进吧
Let's keep moving
危险 禁止入内
我们到了
Well, here we are
到这咱就各走各的了
This is where we part company
过了这个地方  就只有死亡了
Beyond this point lies only death
而且我六点下班
Plus, I clock out at 6:00
玩得开心点
Have fun
危险 禁止入内
危险是吧
Danger, huh?
什么东西都阻止不了我们
Nothing will stop us
做出美味的蟹黄堡
from flipping delicious Krabby Patties
好多了
All better now
抱歉打扰了你的神圣打呼仪式
Sorry to disturb your sacred snoring ritual
我千里迢迢
but I have traveled a long way
从蟹堡王厨房赶过来  只想要
from the kitchen of the Krusty Krab just to get--
不必多言
Say no more
隔油池大师知道海绵宝宝来这的原因
Guru Greasetrap already knows why SpongeBob is here
你要的东西这边都有
We have just what you need
蔬果挖球器
melon ballers
意大利面勺子
spaghetti spoons
煮蛋计时器
egg timers
而且这个巨型香蕉挂可以特价卖给你
and there's also a special on this giant banana hanger
意下如何
What do you say?
都挺不错的
This is all really nice
可我只想修好我心爱的锅铲
but I just need to get my beloved spatula fixed
可以重新锻造好吗
Can you reforge it?
求你快说可以救回铲铲  隔油池先生
Please tell me we can save her, Mr. Greasetrap
就这点要求吗
Is that all?
可以
Sure
两三分钟就能解决
It'll just take a few minutes
我去取一下铁锤和铁砧
Just let the old man grab his ol' hammer and anvil
我来帮你取
Let me get it for ya
不  等等
No, wait
不用怕
Don't worry
我来救你
I'll get you out of there
之后
隔油池要想帮你重新锻造锅铲
Greasetrap cannot reforge your spatula
只能等人家双手先痊愈才行
until my hands have healed up
但你的真命之铲就蕴藏在你的内心
But your true spatula is inside you
好吧
Fine
我可以教你重新锻造
I can teach you to reforge it
谢谢你  大师
Thank you, Master
谢谢
Thank you
记住  你劈的每一掌都是神圣的
Remember, every cut is sacred
不要带着木头
Do not carry the wood
要让木头带领你
let the wood carry you
与火焰融为一体
Become one with the fire
我着火了
I'm one with the fire
大师  时候到了没
Master, is it time yet?
很多很多难受的瞬间之后
他绝对没法准备好
He'll never be ready
我准备好了
I'm ready
你知道吗
You know what?
什么
What?
你成功说服我了
You convinced me
隔油池也认为你准备好了
Greasetrap also thinks you're ready
真的吗
Really?
听到了吗  铲铲
Here that, Spatty
时候总算到了
It is finally time
你总算回来了
You're finally back
说得确实
Finally indeed
我打裤子底感谢你  大师
Thank you from the bottom of my pants, Master
不好了
Oh, no
必须找到回蟹堡王的捷径
I have to find a way back to the Krusty Krab
趁还没太迟赶紧回去
before it's too late
迟
太迟
早
准时
不用怕
Don't worry
隔油池大师知道有条近道
Guru Greasetrap knows a shortcut
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes
我爱惊喜
I love surprises
惊喜
Surprise
神秘雾山停车场
太神了
Amazing
裤头村
迟
太迟
早
准时
时间到
Time's up
工作归你了  海绵汤姆
The job's yours, SpongeTom
好耶
Oh, boy
我的梦想终于实现了
My dreams are finally coming true
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我就知道你会回来  小子
I knew you'd be back, boy-o
而且锅铲也修好了
And I'm not alone
大家听我说  海绵宝宝回来了
SpongeBob's back, everybody
发光发热时间到
It's our time to shine
记住  你的真命之铲蕴藏在你的内心
Remember, your true spatula is inside you
与肉饼融为一体
Become one with the patties
你劈的每一掌都是神圣的
Every cut is sacred
要让蟹黄堡带领你
Let the patties carry you
海绵宝宝  真是太神了
SpongeBob, that was amazing
谢谢  蟹老板
Thanks, Mr. Krabs
一份蟹黄堡  再加一份大份
One Krabby Patty and a large--
你的手怎么了
What happened to your hands?
你的教诲我铭记在心
I remembered what you told me
我向内心深处探寻我的真命之铲
and I went deep within to find my true spatula
我之前说真命之铲蕴藏在内心
When I said your true spatula was inside you
意思是真的就在你心脏旁边
I meant it was literally inside you
好美啊
It's beautiful
最好先洗一下再用
You might want to wash that first
小蜗的小窝
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
Oh, Gary
快出来
Come outside
我有个惊喜要送你
I've got a surprise for you
你一定会爱上的  小蜗
You're gonna love this, Gary
爱死你
really love it
准备好了吗
You ready?
哒哒
Ta-da
是专门给你准备的小窝
It's a playhouse just for you
现在你跟我一样是一家之主了
Now you're a homeowner just like me
不过不用还房贷
minus the mortgage payments
去吧
Go on
进去吧
Go right in
你爱不爱啊
Don't you love it?
是谁住在深海的小小窝里
Who lives in a playhouse under the sea?
没错
That's right
就是你
You
我现在要走了  让你放开了玩
Well, I'm gonna leave you alone to play
玩得开心点
Have fun
小蜗  该进来了
Gary, time to come in
小蜗
Gary?
Gare-bear?
该走了
Come on, buddy
都这么晚了
It's late
得进去了
Time to go inside
不想
No?
你想在你的新小窝里过夜
You wanna spend the night in your new playhouse?
好可爱
That is so cu--
哪来的门
Where'd he get a door?
好
Okay
我
Well, I'm--
我很高兴你喜欢我的礼物
I'm really happy you like my gift
好吧  晚安
Okay, well, good night
海绵宝宝  能不能别吵了
SpongeBob, will you knock off that racket?
不是我
It's not me
什么
What?
不是我
It's not me
是小蜗
It's Gary
拉里
Larry?
那头死龙虾
That lousy lobster
拉里  你个白痴
Larry, you meat head
给我放下你手头上做的事
Whatever you're doing, stop it
我还要睡觉
I need my sleep
第二天早上
小蜗  是你做出来的吗
Gary, did you do this?
小蜗
Gary?
什么
What?
太可爱了
This is so cute
小蜗
Gary
好可爱
This is too cute
我可爱病要犯了
I'm having a cuteness attack
嗨  点点
Hi, Spot
我见过最可爱的东西就这个了
That is the cutest thing I've ever seen
实在太可爱
It's so cute
让我没法呼吸了
I can't breathe
我需要水
I need water
太可爱了
It's too cute
好可爱
Too cute
那个垃圾桶好像章鱼哥家
That garbage can looks like Squidward's house
那只长得像章鱼哥的海胆
That Squidward-looking urchin
一定是小蜗的朋友吧
must be one of Gary's pals
今天还能再可爱到哪去呢
Can this day get any more adorable?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
现在就能了
It can now
把你垃圾桶挪开我
Get your trash can off my--
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
搞什么
What the?
跟那白痴一个样
It looks just like that moron
那什么东西
What's that?
难道是我吗
Is that supposed to be me?
真是
That's
that's
我见过最可爱的东西了
the cutest thing I've ever seen
太可爱了
It's too cute
好可爱
It's cute
太可爱了
It's too cute
可爱
Cute
真可爱
So adorable
可爱
Adorable
可爱过头了
That's just too much
实在可爱
It's so cute
特可爱
Too cute
好可爱
So cute
我们这是在乱叫什么
What are we blubbering about?
好可爱
So cute
可爱可爱可爱
Cutie cutie cute
真可爱
So sweet
好可爱
So cute
特可爱
So adorable
今天最可爱了
This is the cutest day ever
一定会名垂最可爱之史的
in the history of cutest days ever
可爱
Adorable
真可爱
Too cute
太太太太可爱了
Too, too, too, too cute
太太可爱了
Too, too, cute
可爱
Adorable
好可爱
Precious
可爱
Adorable
你家孩子在骚扰我家孩子
Your kids are harassing my kid
人家只是在玩游戏而已
They're just playing a game
没错  我们就快赢了
Yeah, and we're winning
这是游戏
This is a game?
什么
What?
怎么了
What happened?
没事
Nothing
我们只是在支持我们自己的队
We're just rooting for our team
我们队加油
Yay, team us
你队垃圾
Boo, team you
还是别喝汽水比较好
Maybe you should lay off the sodas
今天摄入的糖分已经够多了
You've had enough sugar for today
好
Fine
请来一份甜饼冰淇淋甜筒
One sugar cookie ice cream on a sugar cone, please
多加彩糖粒
with extra sugar sprinkles
可可爱爱的好多小时后
晚安  派大星
Good night, Patrick
晚安  海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob
晚安  派大星
Good night, Patrick
晚安  海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob
晚安  派大星
Good night, Patrick
你们两个能不能闭嘴
Will you two please shut up?
别闹了
Knock it off
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥
Squidward
你们两个昨天哪去了
Where were you two yesterday?
害我得亲自管店  亲自收银
I had to manage, run the register
还要整天亲自做蟹黄堡
and cook all day all by meself
都拿去
Here ya go
烫
Hot
你们就没收过热钱吗
Have you ever had to handle hot change?
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
我们应该是整天沉迷
I guess we got carried away
看我们的动物跟身了
watching our animal double-gaggers all day
那叫分身
That's doppelgangers
不对  那个应该念喷身
No, I believe it's pronounced bubble hangers
你们几个呆头在唠叨什么
What are you barnacle brains blabbering about?
那到底是什么东西
What in Neptune's creation is that?
为什么会这么可爱
And why is it so adorable?
给我挪开
Scooch over
加油  小蟹
Go, Krabsy
小小蟹堡王
A tiny little Krusty Krab
对
Yeah
好可爱
Too cute
好家伙
Oh, boy
接下来是什么
What's next?
一定要瞧瞧
I gotta know
好可爱的观光团
An adorable tour group
饿
Hungry
这个我见过
I think I've seen this one
这个我经历过
I think I lived this one
我的小子就在此时此地度过难关
This was where me boy-o really came through
我的辉煌时刻
My shining moment
印象里没这段啊
I don't remember this part
看来这里只容得下一个我
I guess there's only room for one me
我也是
Or me
我们也是
Or us
很高兴你又回家住了  小蜗
Nice to have you back inside, Gary
也很高兴你们两个也能来一起住
It's nice to have you two here as well
好可爱
Too cute